import React from "react";
import CardForm from "./Components/CardForm";
import "./Styles/App.scss";
import CardList from "./Components/CardList";

class App extends React.Component {
  state = {
    cards: [
      { id: 1, front: "Question", back: "Answer", correct: false },
      { id: 2, front: "Question2", back: "Answer2", correct: false },
      { id: 3, front: "Question3", back: "Answer3", correct: false },
      { id: 4, front: "Question4", back: "Answer4", correct: false },
      { id: 5, front: "Question5", back: "Answer5", correct: false },
      { id: 6, front: "Question6", back: "Answer6", correct: false },
      { id: 7, front: "Question7", back: "Answer7", correct: false },
      { id: 8, front: "Question8", back: "Answer8", correct: false },
      { id: 9, front: "Question9", back: "Answer9", correct: false },
      { id: 10, front: "Question10", back: "Answer10", correct: false }
    ],
    menuOpen: false
  };

  // TOGGLE NEW CARD MENU
  toggleMenu = () => {
    let { menuOpen } = this.state;
    this.setState({
      menuOpen: !menuOpen
    });
  };

  // DELETE CARDS FROM ARRAY
  deleteCards = () => {
    let { cards } = this.state;
    this.setState({
      cards: []
    });
  };

  // GENERATE RANDOM ID
  getId = () => {
    return Math.floor((1 + Math.random()) * 0x10000)
      .toString(16)
      .substring(1);
  };

  //CREATE CARD FOR ARRAY
  createCard = (front, back) => {
    let { cards } = this.state;
    let card = { id: this.getId(), front, back, correct: false };
    this.setState({
      cards: [...cards, card]
    });
  };

  render() {
    let { cards } = this.state;
    return (
      <>
        {this.state.menuOpen ? (
          <div className="overlay">
            <div className="close-menu">
              <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 320 512">
                <path d="M193.94 256L296.5 153.44l21.15-21.15c3.12-3.12 3.12-8.19 0-11.31l-22.63-22.63c-3.12-3.12-8.19-3.12-11.31 0L160 222.06 36.29 98.34c-3.12-3.12-8.19-3.12-11.31 0L2.34 120.97c-3.12 3.12-3.12 8.19 0 11.31L126.06 256 2.34 379.71c-3.12 3.12-3.12 8.19 0 11.31l22.63 22.63c3.12 3.12 8.19 3.12 11.31 0L160 289.94 262.56 392.5l21.15 21.15c3.12 3.12 8.19 3.12 11.31 0l22.63-22.63c3.12-3.12 3.12-8.19 0-11.31L193.94 256z" />
              </svg>
            </div>
            <CardForm toggle={this.toggleMenu} newCard={this.createCard} />
          </div>
        ) : null}
        <div className="container">
          <button className="btn" onClick={this.toggleMenu}>
            Add Card
          </button>
          <button className="btn" onClick={this.deleteCards}>
            Delete Cards
          </button>
        </div>
        <CardList cards={cards} />
      </>
    );
  }
}

export default App;
